Guide to the Whitman College Communications Office Records 1895-2010
Whitman College and Northwest Archives
Whitman College Communication Office Records
1895-2010
Whitman College and Northwest Archives 345 Boyer Avenue Walla Walla, WA 99362 (509) 527-5922 archives@whitman.edu http://www.whitman.edu/archives
HTM_WCA27
Whitman College
36 linear feet 44 boxes
Newspaper clippings and records created by the Whitman College Communications Office
Historical Note
President Clemen created the Office of Public Relations in 1935 to coordinate college publicity and student recruiting activities. He appointed Victor Shawe as the first Director of Public Relations. The current Whitman College Communications Office, part of the Development and College Relations group, is responsible for promoting Whitman College as well as communicating the goals and accomplishments of the college people and departments. The Communications Office publishes Whitman Magazine and The Fountain campus newsletter and manages the college Web site, media relations, and other communications services.
The collection consists of records relating to the Whitman College Communications Office. The collection is divided into six series: News Service, Public Events, Communications Office records, newspaper clippings, and photographic material
By series.
Some of the more current records may be restricted.
Materials are regularly transferred to the Whitman College and Northwest Archives.
Whitman College Communications Office Records, 1895-2010 -- Archives.
Whitman College Communications Office
Media and Communication
The following section contains a detailed listing of the materials in the collection.
- News Service, 1935-1998; Series 1; 4 boxes
  Subject files including press releases, correspondence, reports, itineraries, newspaper articles, photographs, financial records, and pamphlets
  - Budget and financial information, 1935-1939 (Box-folder 3/1)
  - Director of Public Relations Victor Shawe, 1935-1940 (Box-folder 2/2)
  - High school mailing list, circa 1935-1942 (Box-folder 2/1)
  - Victor Shawe, newspaper and high school mailing list, 1936-1937 (Box-folder 2/3)
  - Press Clipping Bureau and clipping services, 1936-1941 (Box-folder 2/4)
  - Correspondence regarding publicity and high school mailing list, 1936-1942 (Box-folder 3/3)
  - Publicity statistics, 1937 (Box-folder 3/2)
  - Press releases, 1939-1974 (Box 1)
  - Who's Who among Students, 1940 (Box-folder 2/5)
  - Publicity statistics, 1940-1942 (Box-folder 3/4)
  - Harper Joy, 1942 (Box-folder 2/6)
  - President Winslow S. Anderson, 1943-1945 (Box-folder 3/5)
  - Whitman Quarterly, Chester Maxey, and material written by Chester Maxey, 1949-1985 (Box-folder 4/2)
  - Time magazine, 1950-1967 (Box-folder 3/9)
  - News releases and newspaper clippings, 1952-1975 (Box-folder 2/7)
  - Whitman College feature in the Seattle Times, 1955-1956 (Box-folder 3/7)
  - Northwest Unlimited magazine article and material relating to News Service, circa late 1950s (Box-folder 3/8)
  - Walter Brattain, 1962-1970 (Box-folder 4/3)
  - College Directory and other material relating to Walla Walla College, 1962-1989 (Box-folder 4/4)
  - Publicity, 1966 (Box-folder 3/10)
  - Annual reports, 1967-1971 (Box-folder 3/11)
  - “U.S. News America’s Best Colleges” and other material relating to Whitman College, 1969-1990 (Box-folder 4/13)
  - Alex MacLeod, Director of News Services, 1970-1973 (Box-folder 2/8-10)
  - Alex MacLeod and Tim Marsh, Directors of News Services, 1973-1974 (Box-folder 2/11)
  - Cushing Eells, circa 1974 (Box-folder 3/12)
  - Donna Chiarelott and Tim Marsh, Directors of News Services, 1974-1978 (Box-folder 2/12-13)
  - Union-Bulletin Progress Editions, 1974-1980 (Box-folder 4/5)
  - News Service, 1975 (Box-folder 3/13)
  - Whitman College Renaissance Consort and arts, 1976-1986 (Box-folder 4/6)
  - “A Strategic Study of Whitman’s Admissions Recruitment Potential in the Seattle Area,” “Whitman Today,” and Communications office, 1978-1988 (Box-folder 4/7)
  - Sports coverage, 1979 (Box-folder 3/14)
  - Student services and awards, 1980-1992 (Box-folder 4/8)
  - Student life, circa 1980s (Box-folder 4/9)
  - Press releases and newspaper articles, 1981-1983 (Box-folder 2/14)
  - Distinguished Secondary School Teacher award, 1982-1991 (Box-folder 4/10)
  - Whitman College’s relationship with the town of Walla Walla, 1982-1991 (Box-folder 4/14)
  - Whitman College sports teams at nationals, 1982-1992 (Box-folder 4/16)
  - Swords of the Samurai arms collection display and Japanese tea ceremony, 1983-1985 (Box-folder 4/11)
  - “Liberal Education” and other material relating to the liberal arts approach, 1984-1989 (Box-folder 4/12)
  - Whitman Sesquicentennial, 1985-1986 (Box-folder 4/19)
  - Visitors' Day, 1985-1990 (Box-folder 4/18)
  - Mary Larson and her seashell collection, 1986 (Box-folder 4/20)
  - Murray Foundation scholarship, 1986 (Box-folder 4/21)
  - Whitman College sports records, 1987-1991 (Box-folder 4/17)
  - New Whitman College logo, 1988 (Box-folder 3/15)
  - Whitman students in the news, 1989-1992 (Box-folder 4/15)
  - Zunes/Wood Peace Mission to Iraq and “Dissent in Time of War” by Stephen Zunes, 1990-1991 (Box-folder 4/22)
  - Whitman College publicity, national rankings, and “The Princeton Review” publications, 1994-1998 (Box-folder 2/15)
  - Agriculture and Forestry plaque, Undated (Box-folder 4/1)
  - Ralph Smith, Undated (Box-folder 3/6)
- Public Events, 1953-2005; Series 2; 6 boxes
  Subject files including brochures, programs, correspondence, advertisements, press releases, contracts, events listings, calendars, schedules, newspaper articles, records, committee members, photographs, critical acclaim, and technical requirements, arranged chronologically
  - Theatrical and musical productions, circa 1904-2000 (Box-folder 5/1)
  - Theatrical and musical productions, 1908-1984 (Box-folder 5/2)
  - Theatrical and musical productions, circa 1917-1990 (Box-folder 5/3)
  - Convocation, prayers and religious services, student body officers, movie showings, refrigerator rental, rides to airport, map of Marcus Whitman’s travel route, and copies of “The Whitman Bulletin”, circa 1920-1991 (Box-folder 5/4)
  - Fine Arts Series, 1954-1964 (Box-folder 5/5)
  - Theatrical and musical productions, 1960-2002 (Box-folder 5/6)
  - Fine Arts Series, 1964-1973 (Box-folder 5/7)
  - Fine Arts Series, 1967-1968 (Box-folder 5/8)
  - Fine Arts Series, 1967-1969 (Box-folder 5/9)
  - Fine Arts Series, 1967-1976 (Box-folder 5/10)
  - Fine Arts Series, 1968-1969 (Box-folder 5/11)
  - Cordiner Hall concerts and lectures, 1968-1973 (Box-folder 5/12)
  - Fine Arts Series, 1969-1971 (Box-folder 5/13)
  - Fine Arts Series, 1969-1971 (Box-folder 5/14)
  - Fine Arts Series, 1970-1971 (Box-folder 5/15)
  - Fine Arts Series, 1970-1972 (Box-folder 5/16)
  - Fine Arts Series, 1971-1972 (Box-folder 5/17)
  - Fine Arts Series, 1971-1973 (Box-folder 5/18)
  - Fine Arts Series, 1972-1973 (Box-folder 5/19)
  - Fine Arts Series, 1973-1974 (Box-folder 5/20)
  - Fine Arts Series, 1974-1977 (Box-folder 5/21)
  - Paul and Stefan Hersh, 1976-1989 (Box-folder 5/22)
  - Jay O'Callahan, 1978-1984 (Box-folder 5/23)
  - Margaret Jenkins Dance Company, 1978-1985 (Box-folder 5/24)
  - Steele Lectureship Endowment, 1978-1987 (Box-folder 5/25)
  - Poster copies and prices, 1979-1980 (Box-folder 5/26)
  - Oberlin Dance Collective, 1979-1984 (Box-folder 5/27)
  - Public events listings and brochures, 1979-1989 (Box-folder 5/28)
  - Public events brochures, 1979-1989 (Box-folder 5/29)
  - Material relating to ethnic dance and music and Dance on Tour, 1979-1991 (Box-folder 5/30)
  - Public Events, 1980-1981 (Box-folder 5/31)
  - Los Angeles Ballet Company, 1980-1983 (Box-folder 5/32)
  - Colorado String Quartet, 1980-1984 (Box-folder 5/33)
  - Soviet Emigre Orchestra, 1980-1984 (Box-folder 5/34)
  - Kathryn Selby, 1980-1984 (Box-folder 5/35)
  - Swanne Alley, 1980-1985 (Box-folder 5/36)
  - Jonathan Miller, 1981-1983 (Box-folder 5/37)
  - Hester Street Klezmer Band, 1981-1983 (Box-folder 5/38)
  - Theatre Mask Ensemble, 1981-1984 (Box-folder 5/39)
  - Rogeri Trio and William Doppmann, 1981-1984 (Box-folder 5/40)
  - Vienna Choir Boys, 1981-1985 (Box-folder 5/41)
  - North Carolina Dance Theatre, 1981-1985 (Box-folder 5/42)
  - Terrence Farrell, 1981-1985 (Box-folder 5/43)
  - Public events, 1982-1983 (Box-folder 5/44)
  - Joseph Eldridge and Washington Office on Latin America, 1982-1983 (Box-folder 5/45)
  - Alex Wilde and “Religion and Revolution in Latin America”, 1983 (Box-folder 5/46)
  - "None of the Above", 1982-1983 (Box-folder 6/1)
  - The Acting Company and “The Merry Wives of Windsor”, 1982-1983 (Box-folder 6/2)
  - William Windom, 1982-1984 (Box-folder 6/3)
  - “The Nutcracker” and the Eugene Ballet Company, 1982-1984 (Box-folder 6/4)
  - John Cottell, 1982-1985 (Box-folder 6/5)
  - Roadside Theatre, 1982-1988 (Box-folder 6/6)
  - “Guide to Internship Development,” student application, and questionnaire relating to internships, 1982-1990 (Box-folder 6/7)
  - Vienna Choir Boys, 1982-1990 (Box-folder 6/8)
  - Scott Cossu, 1982-1995 (Box-folder 6/9)
  - Material relating to the Washington Commission for the Humanities and “Northwest Woman”, 1983 (Box-folder 6/10)
  - Jose Prince, 1983 (Box-folder 6/11)
  - Patricia Ring and the Maryknoll Sisters, 1983 (Box-folder 6/12)
  - “Religion and Revolution in Latin America” symposium, 1983 (Box-folder 6/13)
  - Frances Fitzgerald, 1983 (Box-folder 6/14)
  - John Freimann and “Notes from the Door”, 1983 (Box-folder 6/15)
  - Dick Gregory, 1983-1984 (Box-folder 6/16)
  - Mark Russell, 1983-1984 (Box-folder 6/17)
  - Public events, 1983-1984 (Box-folder 6/18)
  - Marcus Whitman Scientific Symposium, 1983-1984 (Box-folder 6/19)
  - Oregon Repertory Singers, 1983-1984 (Box-folder 6/20)
  - Seymour Hersh, 1983-1984 (Box-folder 6/21)
  - Public events, 1983-1985 (Box-folder 6/22)
  - John Jay and film “Winter Magic Around the World”, 1983-1985 (Box-folder 6/23)
  - Utah Symphony Orchestra, 1983-1985 (Box-folder 6/24)
  - Whitman College trustees and faculty, Founder’s Day, and Nancy Pryor, 1983-1989 (Box-folder 6/25)
  - Uptown Lowdown Jazz Band, 1984 (Box-folder 6/26)
  - The Naked Gershwin, 1984 (Box-folder 6/27)
  - Jack Anderson, 1984 (Box-folder 6/28)
  - Richard Dyer-Bennett and “The Odyssey”, 1984 (Box-folder 6/29)
  - Rebecca Wells and “Splittin’ Hairs”, 1984 (Box-folder 6/30)
  - Whitman to Whitman Relay, 1984 (Box-folder 6/31)
  - Magazine copy of “Savvy” and material relating to Wendy Reid Crisp, 1984 (Box-folder 6/32)
  - La Corte Musical, 1984 (Box-folder 6/33)
  - "Carmen", 1984 (Box-folder 6/34)
  - Washington Commission for the Humanities, 1984 (Box-folder 6/35)
  - George Recker and John Hamilton, 1984-1985 (Box-folder 6/36)
  - Harrison Salisbury, 1984-1985 (Box-folder 6/37)
  - "The Big Broadcast", 1984-1985 (Box-folder 6/38)
  - Alyce Rogers, 1985-1986 (Box-folder 6/39)
  - Preservation Hall Jazz Band, 1984-1986 (Box-folder 6/40)
  - Ballet Folclorico Nacional De Mexico, 1984-1985 (Box-folder 6/41)
  - "Black Women: Achievements Against the Odds" program handbook and material relating to Barbara Thomas, 1984-1985 (Box-folder 6/42)
  - Harry Edwards, 1984-1985 (Box-folder 6/43)
  - Empire Brass Quintet, 1984-1985 (Box-folder 6/44)
  - Marcus Whitman Scientific Symposium, 1984-1985 (Box-folder 6/45)
  - Marcus Whitman Scientific Symposium, 1984-1986 (Box-folder 6/46)
  - Dedication Music Series and International American Music Competition, 1984-1986 (Box-folder 6/47)
  - Zasu Pitts Memorial Orchestra, 1984-1987 (Box-folder 6/48)
  - Gaylan Rowell, 1984-1990 (Box-folder 6/49)
  - Cordelia Wikarski-Miedel and Deborah Dewey, 1985 (Box-folder 6/50)
  - Royal Marines and the Argyll and Sutherland Highlanders, 1985 (Box-folder 6/51)
  - “Dr. Strange Art” lecture by Gary Grant, grant provisions, and Washington Commission for the Humanities booklets, 1985 (Box-folder 6/52)
  - “The Intimate P.D.Q. Bach”, 1985 (Box-folder 6/53)
  - Children’s Ballet Theatre and “Snow White and the Seven Dwarfs”, 1985 (Box-folder 6/54)
  - Main Attraction, 1985 (Box-folder 7/1)
  - Laura Sindell, 1985 (Box-folder 7/2)
  - Opera a la Carte and “The Mikado”, 1985 (Box-folder 7/3)
  - Jackie Torrence, 1985 (Box-folder 7/4)
  - Coretta Scott King, 1985 (Box-folder 7/5)
  - Ski Film Festival, 1985 (Box-folder 7/6)
  - New World Consort, 1985-1989 (Box-folder 7/7)
  - Takacs String Quartet, 1985-1990 (Box-folder 7/8)
  - Photographs, circa 1985 (Box-folder 7/9)
  - Washington Commission for the Humanities grant, 1986 (Box-folder 7/10)
  - “Gotta Sing! Gotta Dance!”, 1986 (Box-folder 7/11)
  - Acting Company and “Much Ado About Nothing”, 1986-1988 (Box-folder 7/12)
  - “The Nutcracker” and the Eugene Ballet Company, 1986-1988 (Box-folder 7/13)
  - Public events, 1986-1989 (Box-folder 7/14)
  - Laser Light Shows, 1986-1991 (Box-folder 7/15)
  - “Presenter’s Profile” reporting form, 1987 (Box-folder 7/16)
  - Public events, 1987-1988 (Box-folder 7/17)
  - Public events, 1987-1988 (Box-folder 7/18)
  - “Anacrusis” tap dance, 1987-1988 (Box-folder 7/19)
  - Daniel McKelway and Stephen Prutsman, 1987-1988 (Box-folder 7/20)
  - “The Velveteen Rabbit” and “Laundry Cycle” dance performances, 1987-1988 (Box-folder 7/21)
  - Empire Brass, 1987-1989 (Box-folder 7/22)
  - London Ballet performance of “A Midsummer Night’s Dream”, 1987-1989 (Box-folder 7/23)
  - Public Events and Utah Phillips, 1987-1989 (Box-folder 7/24)
  - Public events, 1987-1992 (Box-folder 7/25)
  - “Man of La Mancha”, 1988 (Box-folder 7/26)
  - Garrison Keillor, 1988 (Box-folder 7/27)
  - Peter Irons and Gordon Hirabayashi, 1988 (Box-folder 7/28)
  - Mike Murphy, 1988 (Box-folder 7/29)
  - "Miss Minidoka", 1988 (Box-folder 7/30)
  - Montreux, 1988 (Box-folder 7/31)
  - Public events, 1988-1989 (Box-folder 7/32)
  - Public events, 1988-1989 (Box-folder 7/33)
  - Edward Aldwell, 1988-1989 (Box-folder 7/34)
  - John O'Neal and Junebug Jabbo Jones, 1988-1989 (Box-folder 7/35)
  - African Famine and U.S. Surplus Symposium, 1988-1989 (Box-folder 7/36)
  - Dumisani Kumalo, 1988-1989 (Box-folder 7/37)
  - Yahuda Hanani and Leonard Richter, 1988-1990 (Box-folder 8/1)
  - Washington State Arts Commission grant guidelines booklet and material relating to the Arts and Lectures Series, 1988-1990 (Box-folder 8/2)
  - “Worldwatch Paper 85” booklet and material relating to global problems and the GTE Lectureship, 1988-1990 (Box-folder 8/3)
  - Stanley Reeves Plummer and the film showing of “Phantom of the Opera”, 1988-1991 (Box-folder 8/4)
  - The Peking Acrobats, 1988-1992 (Box-folder 8/5)
  - Stephen B. Oates, 1988-1992 (Box-folder 8/6)
  - Computer Services, 1988-1995 (Box-folder 8/7)
  - Michael Lewin, 1989 (Box-folder 8/8)
  - "A Christmas Carol", 1989 (Box-folder 8/9)
  - "Big River" musical, 1989 (Box-folder 8/10)
  - Glenn and Dotty Dorsch, 1989 (Box-folder 8/11)
  - Mike Murphy, 1989 (Box-folder 8/12)
  - George Winston, 1989 (Box-folder 8/13)
  - Daniel Schorr, 1989 (Box-folder 8/14)
  - U.S. Marine Band, 1989 (Box-folder 8/15)
  - Chanticleer, 1989 (Box-folder 8/16)
  - Bowdoin Trio, 1989 (Box-folder 8/17)
  - “Phantom of the Opera”, 1989-1990 (Box-folder 8/18)
  - Ballet Folclorico Nacional de Mexico, 1989-1990 (Box-folder 8/19)
  - Marc Reisner, 1989-1990 (Box-folder 8/20)
  - Neil Sheehan lecture, 1989-1990 (Box-folder 8/21)
  - Galen Rowell, 1989-1991 (Box-folder 8/22)
  - Vancouver Wind Trio, 1989-1991 (Box-folder 8/23)
  - Nylons Concert, 1989-1991 (Box-folder 8/24)
  - Gennady Gerasimov, 1990 (Box-folder 8/25)
  - Sabella Consort, 1990 (Box-folder 8/26)
  - Pei Min Xin, 1990 (Box-folder 8/27)
  - Royal New Zealand Ballet, 1990 (Box-folder 8/28)
  - Hedrick Smith, 1990 (Box-folder 8/29)
  - “The Second City”, 1990 (Box-folder 8/30)
  - Lillian Roybal Rose, 1990 (Box-folder 8/31)
  - Patrick Page and “Passion’s Slaves: An Evening of Shakespeare”, 1990 (Box-folder 8/32)
  - Tziganka, 1990-1991 (Box-folder 8/33)
  - Ridge String Quartet, 1990-1991 (Box-folder 8/34)
  - “The Marriage of Figaro”, 1990-1991 (Box-folder 8/35)
  - Margaret Nessel-Aigner and the Salzburg Chamber Soloists, 1990-1991 (Box-folder 8/36)
  - Ben Vereen and “A Tribute to Broadway”, 1990-1991 (Box-folder 9/1)
  - Side by Side by Sondheim, 1990-1991 (Box-folder 9/2)
  - Michael Doucet and Beausoleil, 1990-1991 (Box-folder 9/3)
  - “The Sound of Music”, 1990-1991 (Box-folder 9/4)
  - Arts and Lecture Series, 1990-1992 (Box-folder 9/5)
  - Lighting estimates and costs, 1990-1992 (Box-folder 9/6)
  - Wayne Cotter and Scott Jones Comedy Night, 1990-1992 (Box-folder 9/7)
  - Bochinche Salsa and Latin Band, 1990-1992 (Box-folder 9/8)
  - Public events committee, 1990-1994 (Box-folder 9/9)
  - Jazz Festival, 1991 (Box-folder 9/10)
  - “Romeo and Juliet”, 1991 (Box-folder 9/11)
  - Jay O'Callahan, 1991 (Box-folder 9/12)
  - Ron Sims, 1991 (Box-folder 9/13)
  - James Fallows, 1991 (Box-folder 9/14)
  - “Real Women Have Curves”, 1991 (Box-folder 9/15)
  - “The Nutcracker” and the Eugene Ballet Company, 1991 (Box-folder 9/16)
  - George Winston, 1991 (Box-folder 9/17)
  - Public events, 1991-1992 (Box-folder 9/18)
  - Ballet Nacional De Caracas, 1991-1992 (Box-folder 9/19)
  - Eddie Daniels Quartet, 1991-1992 (Box-folder 9/20)
  - Omni Films and Omega Control, 1992 (Box-folder 9/21)
  - Arts and Lecture Series, 1992-1993 (Box-folder 9/22)
  - Public events, 1993-1994 (Box-folder 9/23)
  - Public events, 1993-1994 (Box-folder 9/24)
  - Student Services Retreat, 1995 (Box-folder 9/25)
  - Listing of ushers and stagehands, 1995 (Box-folder 9/26)
  - Public events, 1995-1996 (Box-folder 9/27)
  - Whitman Dance Theatre, 1998-2000 (Box-folder 9/28)
  - Mini-Residency Guidebook, Undated (Box-folder 9/29)
  - Event promotion worksheets, Undated (Box-folder 9/30)
  - Whitman College public events calendars and prospective student/admissions informational brochures, 1953-2005 (Box 10)
- Communications Office Records, 1958-2002; Series 3; 6 boxes
  Subject files including correspondence, newspaper articles, reports, records, press releases, brochures, programs, events schedules and calendars, photographs, biographical information, and posters, arranged alphabetically
  - All-College Forum, 1976-1977 (Box-folder 11/1)
  - Atlanta: slain children and Whitman memorial, 1981 (Box-folder 11/2)
  - Big Onion Marathon, 1978-1979 (Box-folder 11/3)
  - Board of Trustees, circa 1977-1980 (Box-folder 11/4)
  - Calendars of activities, 1978-1979 (Box-folder 11/5)
  - President Skotheim’s national fund-raising campaign, 1980 (Box-folder 11/6)
  - President Skotheim’s national fund-raising campaign, 1981 (Box-folder 11/7)
  - President Skotheim’s national fund-raising campaign, 1982 (Box-folder 11/8)
  - President Skotheim’s national fund-raising campaign, 1983 (Box-folder 11/9)
  - President Skotheim’s national fund-raising campaign, 1984-1985 (Box-folder 11/10)
  - President Skotheim’s national fund-raising campaign, 1985 (Box-folder 11/11)
  - President Skotheim’s national fund-raising campaign, 1986 (Box-folder 11/12)
  - President Skotheim’s national fund-raising campaign, 1986-1987 (Box-folder 11/13)
  - “The Campaign for Whitman: Times” magazine, 1984, 1987 (Box-folder 11/14)
  - “Campaign Watch 2000” (Box-folder 11/15)
  - “Case Recognition – Excellence in News Writing”, 1982 (Box-folder 11/16)
  - “Case Recognition – Excellence in Public Information”, 1982 (Box-folder 11/17)
  - “Case Recognition – News and Information”, 1982 (Box-folder 11/18)
  - “Case Recognition – Public Relations Projects”, 1982 (Box-folder 11/19)
  - “Case Recognition – Excellence in News Writing”, 1983 (Box-folder 11/20)
  - “Case Recognition” journalism program, 1983 (Box-folder 11/21)
  - “Case District Communication Awards Competition”, 1983-1984 (Box-folder 11/22)
  - “Case District 8 News Writing Competition”, 1984 (Box-folder 11/23)
  - “Case Recognition” journalism program and “Great Ideas” magazine, 1986 (Box-folder 11/24)
  - “Case Recognition” journalism program, 1988 (Box-folder 11/25)
  - “Case Recognition” journalism awards, 1989 (Box-folder 11/26)
  - “Case Recognition” journalism awards and David Maxwell, 1989-1990 (Box-folder 11/27)
  - Commencement, 1966-1984 (Box-folder 11/28)
  - Commencement and graduates, 1976-1977 (Box-folder 11/29)
  - Commencement and seniors, 1977-1978 (Box-folder 11/30)
  - Commencement, graduates, and Harry Woolf, 1979 (Box-folder 11/31)
  - Commencement, 1984 (Box-folder 11/32)
  - Commencement, 1985 (Box-folder 11/33)
  - Commencement, 1986 (Box-folder 11/34)
  - Commencement, 1987 (Box-folder 11/35)
  - Commencement, 1988 (Box-folder 11/36)
  - Commencement and “Distinguished Teaching Award”, 1989 (Box-folder 11/37)
  - Commencement address and honored alumni, 1990 (Box-folder 11/38)
  - Commencement speaker and honored alumni, 1991 (Box-folder 11/39)
  - Commencement, 1992 (Box-folder 12/1)
  - Commencement, Doris Bounds, and student, alumni, and community awards, 1992-1994 (Box-folder 12/2)
  - Commencement, 1993 (Box-folder 12/3)
  - Commencement and Inauguration speakers, 1994 (Box-folder 12/4)
  - Commencement, inauguration speeches, and Thomas Cronin, 1994 (Box-folder 12/5)
  - Communications guide, 1988 (Box-folder 12/6)
  - Commission on Higher Schools, the All-College Forum, Commission on Colleges, Whitman College Indian Hills Conference and Salishan Faculty Retreat, 1967-1984 (Box-folder 12/7)
  - Convocation, 1990-1991 (Box-folder 12/8)
  - Convocation, 1992 (Box-folder 12/9)
  - Convocation, 1993 (Box-folder 12/10)
  - Convocation, 1994 (Box-folder 12/11)
  - Cookie Lady Paula Bemrose, 1997 (Box-folder 12/12)
  - Crimes and accidents, 1985-2002 (Box-folder 12/13)
  - Dean of Faculty papers: course load reduction, scholarship support, faculty expertise, medical school acceptance, Visitors’ Day, computer software, and retirement, 1968-1988 (Box-folder 12/14)
  - Debate and speech competitions, 1982-1984 (Box-folder 12/15)
  - Debate, 1985-2005 (Box-folder 12/16)
  - Defense Waste Symposium and Senator Robert Stafford, 1987-1988 (Box-folder 13/1)
  - Whitman College faculty and staff expertise, Undated (Box-folder 13/2)
  - Whitman College faculty and staff expertise, Undated (Box-folder 13/3)
  - Features: Clock tower, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 13/4)
  - Features: Santa story, 1983 (Box-folder 13/5)
  - Features: Staff written, 1980 (Box-folder 13/6)
  - Features: Staff written, 1981 (Box-folder 13/7)
  - Features: Staff written, 1982 (Box-folder 13/8)
  - Features: Staff written, 1983 (Box-folder 13/9)
  - Features: stories about Whitman students, 1981-1984 (Box-folder 13/10)
  - Filmmaking Boot Camp, 1998 (Box-folder 13/11)
  - Four-credit course changes, 1967-1968 (Box-folder 13/12)
  - Freedom of speech, 1964-1973 (Box-folder 13/13)
  - Freshman profiles, 1965-1969 (Box-folder 13/14)
  - Freshman questionnaire results, 1968 (Box-folder 13/15)
  - Freshman Seminar, 1976-1977 (Box-folder 13/16)
  - Gifts and grants and M.J. Murdock Charitable Trust, 1980-1986 (Box-folder 13/17-18)
  - Ross Good mugging and injury, Whitman Men’s Soccer, 2002 (Box-folder 13/19-20)
  - Governing Boards of Whitman College: names and address listings, 1923-1978 (Box-folder 13/21)
  - Governor’s Art Award application, 1994 (Box-folder 13/22)
  - Grading system proposed change, 1968-1976 (Box-folder 13/23)
  - Graduate study advisors, 1970 (Box-folder 13/24)
  - Grants and grant proposals, 1967-1977 (Box-folder 13/25)
  - Hanford radiation issues, 1979-1994 (Box-folder 13/26)
  - Theatre fire and new theatre design, 1958-1959 (Box-folder 13/27)
  - Harper Joy Theatre dedication, 1967 (Box-folder 13/28)
  - Harper Joy Theatre, 1959-1983 (Box-folder 13/29)
  - Harper Joy Theatre, 1977-1978 (Box-folder 13/30)
  - Harper Joy Theatre and “Steambath”, 1978-1979 (Box-folder 13/31)
  - Harper Joy Theatre, 1979-1980 (Box-folder 13/32)